# Mei Lin

#### Software QA tester

Email: linmeiQA@gmail.com, Tel: 514-833-1653

# Summary

Software QA tester with full system development lifecycle experience, including designing, developing and implementing test plans, test cases and test processes fueling swift corrective actions, significant cost savings and fault-free audits.

Hands-on technology professional accustomed to working in complex, project-based agile environments. Multifaceted experience in QA software testing, software development and user-acceptance testing.

#### **Skills Summary:**

SQA Testing & Methodologies
Test Plans, Cases & Processes
Functional Requirements
Scripting & Documentation
Regression & Negative Testing
UI & Compatibility Testing
Data Interface & Migration Testing
Performance/Load/Stress Testing
Testing Automation
Defect/Bug Tracking
Test Strategies & Coverages

## **Technology Skills:**

Visual Studio 2017/2015, SQL Server2016/2008, T-SQL, BIDS, ASP.NET, C#.NET, C++, HTML, JavaScript, XML, Oracle, IIS, SSIS, PowerShell Script, Jmeter, Git, Github, Jira, BYOD, Wdesk, Jenkins, SpecFlow, Microsoft Azure Service Fabric, BI, Datawarehouse, SAS, Microsoft Access, Unix, etc.

# Experience

QS Engineer at Worldpay October 2013 - Present

• Developing test plan and design and develop complete, end-to-end testing strategies;

- Participating in the execution of procedures for ensuring the quality and serviceability of new features and releases of software;
- Developing test protocols and scripts based on business, functional, and non-functional requirements;
- Authoring and executing test cases, using defined methodologies for manual and/or automated tests:
- Executing Automation test suite.
- Updating methods and procedures to ensure continuous improvement to software quality assurance and serviceability standards;
- Isolating, reproducing, and tracking bugs and verifies fixes;
- Analyzing test results to ensure existing functionality and recommends corrective action;
- Maintaining and modifying test environment and configuration as needed;
- Creating new test environments and configurations to meet test cases or problem recreation requirements;
- Documenting test results, manage and maintains defect and test case databases to assist in the continuous improvement and modification of software;
- Assisting in the assessment and planning of test efforts required for new functions/features under development;
- Working with software developers in resolution of problems;
- Providing support to stakeholders in the execution of testing activities;
- Gathering the detailed testing requirements for the various projects, deliver the iterative test strategy, plan, traceability, conduct manual/automated testing, and assist in tracking/fixing defects; and,
- Working with business and project team to ensure project success.
- Project using: BYOD, Wdesk, Visual Studio 2017/2015, SQL Server2016/2008, T-SQL, BIDS,C#.NET,C++, HTML, JavaScript, XML, IIS, SSIS, Jmeter, PowerShell Script, Git, Github, Jira, Jenkins, SpecFlow, Microsoft Azure Service Fabric, etc.

## IT Specialist at Jessica Pastries

February 2008 - March 2011 (3 years 2 months)

BI and ETL

- Successfully load the data to SQL Server2008 and analyze and explain the result using SQL Server 2008 and Access as an important tool.
- Using different databases cross-reference other database with Primary Key, Foreign Key and linking their related knowledge together.
- Retrieve and modify data using SQL Server2008 and BIDS and acquire information from different database.
- Generated complex database reports use complex SQL queries including single row function, table join, subquery, group function and set operations.

### Reporting

Prepare reports including: inventory, sales, shipping using Crystal Reports.

## Software developer

Develop the whole life-cycle of ERP system, from user requirement analysis, system design, implementation, testing and documenting, deployment and maintenance.

This ERP system includes .the following modules: R&D, Costing, Customer Quotes, O/E, Purchasing, Inventory, Warehousing, Shipping, Invoicing, Quality Control, Labeling, Barcoding, and Employee Shift Etc.

#### IT Specialist at Comexico Inc.

January 2003 - February 2008 (5 years 2 months)

Warehouse and Shipping system management.

# IT Specialist at PING AN INSURANCE (GROUP) COMPANY OF CHINA ,LTD September 1993 - October 2000 (7 years 2 months)

#### Programmer

- Develop CRM & process module using FoxPro/FoxBASE.
- Integrate different systems, centralizing data center
- · Write technical documents

#### Database Administrator

- Maintain database: Oracle, MS Access, FoxBASE
- Backup & Recovery, Performance tuning, etc.

#### Reporting

• Building reports, KPI's, statistics, dashboards, and graph's based on need/s using MS Access, SQL, PL/SQL and Crystal Report.

#### System Administrator

- Proactively monitor the status of all IT infrastructures and Report
- Manage network operations: Novell, NT, WAN, LAN (routers, switches (3Com and Cisco), DHCP, DNS, VPN), IIS Server, proxy, Firewall, anti-virus security management, Exchange Server, print servers etc.
- Maintain mainframe servers (HP-UNIX) and workstations.
- Create and maintain user profiles, groups and user accounts. Involves ensuring accuracy of accounts against current employee groups

#### **Technical Support**

Maintain servers and workstations (PCs and laptops) hardware, software, network, and peripheral
equipment. Involves troubleshooting and responding quickly to reported issues and setting
priorities when confronted with numerous issues

## Education

Victoria Training Center (Montreal), 2017 ~ 2018 C#.NET, Software Architecture, SAS

USALaoTu , 2012-2013 Certificate, BI, SQL Server

Tyark College, Montreal, 2008 Certificate, Data Warehousing, BI

Concordia University, 2000-2001 Graduate Diploma, Computer Science

Oracle University, Year 2000 Certificate, Oracle DBA

Microsoft Certification training, 1999-2000 MCSE certificate

Novell Education Center, 1996 - 1997 Certificate, Novell IntranetWare CNE

Donghua University,1989 - 1993

Bachelor's Degree Computer Science

Language:

English, French, Chinese



https://www.linkedin.com/in/mei-lin-22611267/